SOFTWARE ENGINEER · FRONT-END DEVELOPE

Lisboa, Portugal

"One day Alice came to a fork in the road and saw a Cheshire cat in a tree. 'Which road do I take?' she asked. 'Where do you want to go?' was his response. 'I don't know,' Alice answered. 'Then,' said the cat, 'it doesn't matter."

Summary_

Javascript developer with a passion for web and software development. I'm a professional with an excellent work ethic and a loyal worker focusing on the best outcomes. I've got a strong team spirit and a lot of humor. I have experience working with many frameworks and libraries, including AngularJS, Angular and Ionic. My front-end development approach follows best practices as well as usability guidelines with performance awareness. I always try to find the most scalable and modular solution for a problem, in order to avoid wasting time in the near future. Mobile compatibility is one of my main concerns, so I always focus on making my apps work on mobile devices nice and smooth.

Work Experience _____

Lisboa, Portugal

FRONT-END ENGINEER 2019 - PRESENT

- Optimization of client-facing assets, while considering user experience
- Building new features for the product
- Mostly Vue.js and some PHP
- · Code review and testing within the team

Helpr Tech Lisboa, Portugal

FRONT-END ENGINEER 2016 - 2019

- I'm responsible for the development of helpr's CMS.
- It was built with Angular (with unit testing) and it is responsive.
- Features include the ability to send, filter and target push notifications to specific audiences on mobile phones. As well as user listing, content editing and analytics.
- My concerns involve code quality, testability and consistent project structure.
- At the same time, I help with the development of hybrid apps, using Ionic.
- AngularJS, Angular and Ionic Framework. SCSS.

bimK Oeiras, Portugal

FULL STACK DEVELOPER 2015 - 2016

- Developed a Sims-like portal, that offered object for architects to use in their projects.
- I was responsible for developing the analytics front-end, allowing for the user to switch between various chart types, and view statistics by country, in a world-map.
- Play framework, AngularJS HTML5 and SCSS. PostgreSQL, Java, ElasticSearch.

Museu Nacional de História Natural e da Ciência

Lisboa, Portugal

Web developer

TRAINEE

2014 - 2016

- Designed the museum's website structure and created it in Drupal.
- In a different project, I helped to structure a citizen science platform.

Innovation Makers Oeiras, Portugal

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

• Developed a server side prototype for a banking kiosk.

2014 (summer intership)

- Experimenting a websockets protocol to establish the connection between the server and the interface.
- C#, websockets. Javascript, HTML.

Primedrinks Lisboa, Portugal

• Setup required systems, maintaining network structure, helpdesk.

- 2013 (summer internship)
- Overall intersting experience, mainly because of daily contact with people: understanding their needs and figure the best quality/cost solution.
- · Microsoft technologies.

INEDC-ID Lisboa, Portugal

FULL STACK DEVELOPER 2012 (summer internship)

- Development of a serious game aiming to explain the basic life support protocol.
- · C# and Unity game engine.
- Awarded with a grade of 17/20 by the jury.
- · web.tecnico.ulisboa.pt/jorge.s.filipe/work/sbv

Education

Instituto Superior Técnico, Universidade de Lisboa

Oeiras, Portugal

MASTERS IN INFORMATION SYSTEMS AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

2013 - 2015

- My thesis, "Where Have I Been Visualizing Personal Geolocation Data" explored visual queries with personal semantics, regarding personal geolocation data.
- Data cleaning of GPS tracks smoothing of paths and error removal.
- · Spatial databases and queries based on the tracks, find information like: in which days did I spent more than 5 hours at University.
- Visual querying interface simple drag and edit interface to reproduce queries in an easy way.
- Python, PostGIS, Javascript, HTML.
- avg. grade: 16/20

Instituto Superior Técnico, Universidade de Lisboa

Lisboa, Portugal

BACHELOR IN INFORMATION SYSTEMS AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

2010 - 2013

• avg. grade: 13/20

Highschool

Escola Secundária Damião de Goes

Alenquer, Portugal

2007 - 2010

Science and Technology

Extracurricular Activity

LAGE2 - Laboratório de Apoio à Gestão de Actividades Extracurriculares dos Estudantes

Oeiras, Portugal

DIRECTOR OF OPERATIONS AND EVENTS AND VICE PRESIDENT

2014 - 2015

- Event coordination and management in a student group at IST-Taguspark.
- Planning workshops, conferences and talks for the campus students.

Instituto Superior Técnico, Universidade de Lisboa

Oeiras, Portugal

TEDxIST organizer

2015

· Part of TEDxIST 2015 team.

- With previous experience, helped the team to succeed on another edition of TEDxIST.

Instituto Superior Técnico, Universidade de Lisboa

Oeiras, Portugal

TEDXIST COORDINATOR

2014

- TEDxIST 2014 host and coordinator.
- Team leader in the planning of the event, from October to March.

ALAMBI - Associação para o estudo e defesa do ambiente do concelho de Alenquer

Alenguer, Portugal

ENVIRONMENTAL VOLUNTEER

2009 - 2016

- Creation and maintenance of the website.
- · Publication and presentation of environmental related material.

Skills.

Development

· HTML5, CSS3, Javascript ES6 (Functional, Modular and Object Oriented), Single Page Applications, Crossbrowser Compatibility, Git.

APIs

• REST APIs, Google Maps API.

Javascript frameworks

• AngularJS, Angular, Ionic, Selenium, Protractor.

Soft skills

• Enthusiasm, problem solving, teamwork, decision making, quick learning, determination, responsibility, proactivity, result-driven.

Interests

• Multimedia, interfaces, web development, programming, computer science, tech conferences, game development, serious games, quantified self, photography, bike, swimming, traveling.